Don't look for a reason... Look for a way out.
Cube is a thriller, science fiction, mystery film directed by Vincenzo Natali.
A group of strangers find themselves trapped in a maze-like prison.
It soon becomes clear that each of them possesses the peculiar skills
necessary to escape, if they don't wind up dead first.
Leaven, played by Nicole De Boer.
Holloway, played by Nicky Guadagni.
Quentin, played by Maurice Dean Wint.
Worth, played by David Hewlett.
Kazan, played by Andrew Miller.
Rennes, played by Wayne Robson.
Cube is a 1997 Canadian science fiction horror film
directed and co-written by Vincenzo Natali.
A product of the Canadian Film Centre's First Feature Project, Nicole de Boer, Nicky Guadagni, David Hewlett, Andrew Miller, Julian Richings,
Wayne Robson, and Maurice Dean Wint star as seven individuals trapped in a bizarre and deadly labyrinth of cube-shaped rooms.
Cube gained notoriety and a cult following for its surreal and
Kafkaesque setting in industrial, cube-shaped rooms.
It received generally positive reviews and led to a series of films.
A Japanese remake was released in 2021.
The film explores themes of escape, entrapment, riddle, autism, mathematics.
The tone is mind_bending and thought_provoking and intense.